# 今天用带鱼做凉菜
Today we use beltfish to cook a cold dish.
# 搅拌一下 巧克力色
Mix it a little, chocolate color.
# 黑醋带鱼卷
balsamic vinegar beltfish roll
# 绝对好吃
Absolutely tasty!
# 小东北 来自于东北 东北人
Xiao Dongbei comes from Northeast China
# 今天我发现这个带鱼有点奇怪
I found today’s hairtail a little strange.
# 这么大眼 有点像三叔的眼
The eyes are so huge. They look like San Shu’s eyes.
# 大眼瞪小眼
Uneven eyes.
# 东海带鱼 一看这带鱼就不错
Today's beltfish is from the East China Sea. You can tell how good the quality is from its appearance.
# 咱就开始吧
Let’s start.
# 鲜带鱼 来的时候要把鳞
Fresh hair tail. At first you need to
# 给刮干净了
Scale the beltfish.
# (带鱼去头尾)
(Cut off the head and tail)
# 它算无鳞鱼的一部分
It is a type of scaleless-fish
# 其实它外边这种白膜 就算它的鳞
Actually, this layer of membrane out there, is its scale.
# 有的进口带鱼又肥又大
Some of the imported hairtails are big and juicy.
# 但是它脊背上有两个疙瘩 石骨
But there are two knots on its spine, which are called Shi Gu (rock bone).
# 你看这是石骨
Check out the knots.
# 一般正宗舟山带鱼里边是没有石骨的
Normally, authentic beltfish from Zhoushan do not have Shi Gu.
# 你看一眼这石骨
Have a look on it.
# 它这肉比较肥大
The meat is thick.
# 但是它有一个不好的地方 有点腥
But there is a downside. It's a little bit fishy.
# 尤其在石骨那位置 特别腥
Especially at its Shi Gu area, extremely fishy.
# 葱姜水 倒点黄酒
Scallion and ginger juices, a little bit rice wine.
# 葱姜水放好了 来点底味 来点盐
After that, add on some base taste, a little bit salt.
# 黄酒有了 盐
Rice wine is good, so as salt.
# 要腌制 很简单
It’s simple to marinate.
# 这个鱼葱姜水 黄酒腌完之后
After beltfish is marinated with ginger juice, scallion juice, and rice wine,
# 然后咱们用厨房用纸
We use kitchen towel
# 把它的水分蘸干
to dry the fish
# 然后再卷
And then roll up the beltfish.
# 刚才闻这鱼还真有点腥
The beltfish was fishy a moment ago
# 通过他腌制以后这腥味你看 没了
Now the odor is removed by the marination.
# 你闻闻 一点都没了
Smell it, its odorless now.
# 就剩盆味了 他处理的很好
Only the smell of the pot remains. He did a really good job.
# 开始卷了师父
Now I start to roll the fish, master.
# 这一条卷几个
How many rolls can a fish filet make?
# 一条相当于四卷吧
Four.
# 这么大就行了
This is the right size.
# 咱们家里边根据个人的喜好
You can adjust the size as you like.
# 一条卷四卷 这卷真不小
Four roll per fish. The size is massive.
# 半条鱼下去了
Half of the fish is used.
# 知道大爷能吃
I know Da Ye has a good appetite.
# 用牙签咱们给它固定上 这方法好
Secure the roll with a toothpick. This is a smart method.
# 然后等一下就插好就风干
After this, get the fish air dried.
# 风干多长时间 风干一小时吧
How long does it take? Around a hour.
# 你看见没还得修一下
You should trim the edges as well.
# 讲究 还跟花似的 你看多美
Exquisite! Like gardening flowers. Look how beautiful it is!
# 你看如果说我们家里要是自己做
If you cook at home,
# 就不用这样了 没必要
It’s not necessary to do this step.
# 我要喜欢吃这些怕浪费
In this way, you won't waste any of the fish.
# 直接改成段 也一样吃是吧
You don't even have to roll it up. Just cut it into chunks and it would taste the same
# 我拿去风干 然后咱们熬个醋
I’ll take it to air-drying. Now we prepare the balsamic glaze.
# 就放自己家窗边风干个一小时就行
You can put it near the window for air-drying. For an hour.
# 熬醋的时间就可以了
It will be good after we finish cooking balsamic glaze.
# 然后拿电扇吹行不行 那最好了
Can you use a fan for air-drying? That will be the best.
# 最好家里熬醋用铝锅是最好的
It is best to use an aluminium wok to prepare the vinegar sauce.
# 铁锅跟醋熬出来之后
If you use an iron wok,
# 它有股铁生锈的味道
The sauce would have a metallic taste.
# 什么醋 这是意大利黑醋
What vinegar it is? It’s balsamic vinegar.
# 但是咱们在家做根据个人的喜好
But as always, you can choose any vinegar you like.
# 比如你是山西人
For instance, if you are from Shanxi,
# 可以用陈醋 用香醋
You can use aged dark vinegar, or Zhenjiang vinegar.
# 你是哪的人用哪的醋
You can always choose your local vinegars.
# 其实黑醋它一般的酸味不容易走
The acid of balsamic vinegar doesn't evaporate as easily
# 这是冰片糖 两块
This is golden slab sugar. Two pieces.
# 过去粤菜常用的 很容易买到
It was widely used in Guangdong cuisine. You can get it in most grocery stores.
# 冰糖 半瓶醋的话
Chinese rock sugar, half bottle of vinegar.
# 也就是二百五十克
It’s around 250g.
# 熬醋的时候必须放点姜
Ginger is a must for this vinegar glaze
# 为啥 它有一股果香的味道
Why? Because it has a fruity taste.
# 意大利醋它的酸味是稳定的
The taste of balsamic vinegar is stable.
# 因为它是果蔬酿造出来的
Because it is made from fruit.
# 就是它不易挥发
In other words, it’s less-volatile.
# 镇江香醋就完全可以
Zhenjiang vinegar is a good alternative as well.
# 米醋就差点 颜色不行
Rice vinegar won't work as well. The color is not strong enough.
# 米醋熏醋都差点
Neither does smoked vinegar.
# 家里边就冰糖 冰糖就可以
For home cooking, rock sugar is fine.
# 放点姜 没那么多要求
Put in some ginger. It’s not that strict.
# 酒店他对出品要求严格一点
The hotel will have a higher standard of the food quality.
# 熬多长时间 熬二十分钟吧
How long for reducing? Around 20 minutes.
# 熬化了它 然后让醋有粘稠度
Until the rock sugar dissolves, which will thickens the glaze.
# 咱们家里燃气灶这是最大的火了
This is the highest heat we can get at home.
# 大火烧就行
It’s good.
# 带鱼炸么 炸
Do we fry the beltfish? Yes.
# 必须的 不炸还行
We have to deep fry the fish.
# 这熬醋的时间咱就可以炸带鱼了
Let's fry the fish while the vinegar reduces.
# 熬黑醋的时候火不用降
Keep the heat
# 一直大火就行了
At the high level all the time.
# 收到自己的想要的粘稠度就ok了
Reduce it until you are happy with the consistency
# 带鱼刚才咱们风干了一个小时
Now the beltfish has been air dried for an hour.
# 就成这种颜色
The color turns into this.
# 然后外皮干了
And skin is dry.
# 干的炸出来颜色更好看  更金黄色
The color will look better when the surface is dry. More golden brown.
# 你看慢慢拉黏了 开始粘稠了
Check out the glaze. It’s getting thick now.
# 这颜色挺漂亮的
The color looks wonderful.
# 发亮了 发红发亮了
It’s getting brighter. And it turns red.
# 二伯您看黑醋跟姜的结合
Er Bai, check the combination of the balsamic vinegar and ginger.
# 出来一种可乐的味道 果香的味道
They smell like coke, very fruity.
# 让人一闻
An adorable smell.
# 二伯陶醉了
Er Bai is indulging in it.
# 可以了 油温六成 开始炸了
It’s ready. 60% heat (180°C). Now we start to fry.
# 炸完这鱼的油 能用么还
Is the oil reusable after frying the fish?
# 能用啊 然后我们加点葱姜 再熬一个
Absolutely. Fry some scallion and ginger in it.
# 这不就成葱油了么 没错
Then it becomes scallion-ginger oil, no? Exactly.
# 所以二伯说了
As Er Bai said,
# 剩下的油可以熬葱油 可以炒菜
the rest of the oil can be used for making scallion oil. It can be used for stir-frying.
# 炸带鱼这东西
When frying the beltfish,
# 搁进锅里就不要动它 不要理它
Don’t move it around too much. Leave it alone.
# 它什么时候壳挺了以后再动
You can move it until the skin sets and turns crispy.
# 否则的话它容易碎
Otherwise the meat would crumble.
# 看见没有开始粘稠了
Check out, it’s getting thick.
# 一看就地道 带鱼的香味出来了
Authentic! The aroma of the beltfish comes out.
# 咱炸到这个程度就捞出来
Deep fry the fish rolls until they looks like this, and get them out.
# 然后还得复炸一遍
And fry them one more time.
# 完了把牙签取下来
After that, remove the toothpicks.
# 漂亮
Beautiful.
# 大爷讲话好漂亮
As Da ye said, it’s beautiful.
# 好漂亮啊
Surely.
# 你看这油炸完以后多新
Look how fresh the oil is even after the frying.
# 吹干吹的好
Because we did a good job air-drying.
# 把牙签去掉
Remove the toothpicks.
# 因为你要是直接炸定型
Because if you leave those toothpicks in all the way till the end,
# 牙签不好取了 扎在里头了
They would be difficult to take out.
# 这次油温就是七成热的油温下
Now the temperature is 70% (210°C).
# 复炸的时候油温要升高一些
The second time, the oil temperature is higher.
# 差不多了吧
Is it good?
# 现在就可以搁冰箱了
Now put it into the fridge.
# 黏度起来了 （醋）关火
The thickness of the vinegar is prefect. Turn off the heat.
# 盛出来搁冰箱里边
Put it into the fridge.
# 上窗户那吹去吧
Put it under the window.
# 黑醋得凉一下才能挂住带鱼
Cool it down so it becomes thick enough to stick to the surface of the fish roll.
# 因为它加了很多糖
Because we added a lot of sugar
# 让它沉淀晾凉以后它更黏
It will be thicker and stickier when it cools down.
# 达到这种金黄色就ok了
It’s good once it turns golden brown.
# 这个需要晾么
Air cooling?
# 这个需要晾一下 更脆
Yes. It will be crispier.
# 晾凉了 然后熬好的黑醋
After the vinegar cooled down,
# 你看看 色重粘稠
it is getting thicker and darker.
# 开始制作了 倒进去
Now we pour it in.
# 拌匀 搅拌一下 巧克力色
Mix them altogether. A chocolate color.
# 漂亮漂亮
Beautiful!
# 这就可以出盘了
Now we can plate the dish.
# 油亮黑黑 有点像三叔的脸
Black and shiny. It’s like San shu’s face.
# 留白 甩汁留白
Leave some space.
# 芝麻
Sesame.
# 来点小绿草
Little bit of green.
# 这句话说的有点像东北人 小绿草
You speak like a Dongbeier. Green.
# OK
Ok
# 意大利黑醋带鱼卷
Balsamic vinegar beltfish roll.
# 就这么成功了 顺利的完成了
Now we finished the dish successfully.
# 绝对好吃
It’s gonna taste good!
# 二伯怎么样
How does it taste, Er Bai?
# 这道菜是最早师父教我的
This is the first dish that my master taught me before.
# 今天给师父交作业
Today I present the dish to my master.
# 让师父先尝一下
Let the master taste first.
# 你看看 好太好了
Good. It’s great.
# 师父嘴小了点
Master has a small mouth.
# 有点像大眼带鱼
Looks like the beltfish we cooked today.
# 真酥啊 二伯
It’s so crispy, Er Bai.
# 真好吃
Delicious.
# 吃到意大利味儿没有
Are there any Italian taste?
# 感觉有女朋友的感觉
It has a taste just like my girlfriend.
# 酥劲儿脆劲儿
Crispiness.
# 做中国菜的境界是什么 是融合
What is the highest level of cooking Chinese cuisine? It’s the fusion.
# 最高境界融合 他融合的好
The highest level, fusion. He did a great job.
# 这孩子把中国菜
This kid combined Chinese food
# 和世界的调味品加以融合
with foreign ingredient very well.
# 又成为中国菜的另一个口味
And it becomes a new dish of Chinese cuisine.
# 按照三叔的一句话一通百通
According to San Shu’s words, “ You know the key you know them all.”
# 海纳百川 融汇贯通
The sea embraces all rivers and streams.
# 其实最重要的是什么
The most important thing is,
# 使我们的中餐在成菜形式下
Adjusting the plating of Chinese food
# 跟国际上接轨了
to make it more appealing for international audience
# 就是这样
Exactly.
# 烹小鲜治大国 走
Cooking a small delicacy is just like governing a large country.
# import ending.srt 00:08:14,150 请原样保留此行